<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>talks/podcasts 🎧 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/talks/</link><description>Recent content in talks/podcasts 🎧 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Acko on AIR - Subrata Mitra, Abhinav Chaturvedi (Accel Partners)' with Varun</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</guid><description>​
Talk: Acko on AIR - Subrata, Abhinav (Accel Partners, Acko&amp;rsquo;s first investors) - at Acko townhall
Notes:
Anecdote by Abhinav - Sachin Bansal (his then colleague at Amazon) fixed code in amazon payment for which the team was struggling (system was crashing completely when running a test suite cos of which they were unable to launch) Flipkart initial investment by Subrata - 3.5 cr for 25% - everytime they would come they talk about something they fixed (everyday) - committed to the cause When looking for investment - references from networks matter (Accel will ask Varun for Acko&amp;rsquo;s employee) Why most startups fail get to some scale as quickly as possible (zero to one) not having sharp focus (anti of why win - having a sharp focus) team dynamics don&amp;rsquo;t workout, going out in different directions Advice to youngsters Abhinav, Subrata - work with really good people, it compounds (good mentor) Subrata - really enjoy working whatever you do Varun - stay with a team for long time (5yrs or so it takes to crack a market) - everything compounds - your skills, your market value, your networks (you don&amp;rsquo;t restart everytime) One trait which Abhinav looks for in early founders - mentally and physically fit - it is tough to maintain Acko vision - 10Bn dollar (by 2030), in market that compounds Make companies in bust (startup bubble, less distractions), they will come out on top (strong) when the market is out of bust, market cycle again starts (happened multiple times in past - 9/11, 2008 etc)</description></item><item><title>'Masters of Scale - Eric Schmidt with Reid Hoffman</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</guid><description>​
Eric Schmidt was Executive Chairman of Google’s parent company, Alphabet, Inc. From 2001 to 2011 he was CEO of Google. Previously, he was CEO of Novell and before that a long-time executive at Sun Microsystems.
Notes:
HOFFMAN: Amit eventually built a tool that accurately predicts how much revenue the company had at any given time, down to the second. Pranks and productivity tend to blend together at Google, which is why Eric doesn’t dwell on the question of why Amit moved in to begin with.</description></item><item><title>'Experimenting with content' by Sattvik Mishra</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</guid><description> ​
Talk: Sattvik Mishra: Experimenting with content
Who: ScoopWhoop CEO
SOTS:
Traditional media houses prioritizes news for you (in a generic way, by giving more space on newspaper and time on tv-shows, also by ordering and grouping same genre together) News is subjective, for some it could be a spoiler in game of thrones, for others it could be sports. To create awareness on unconventional topics, make it relatable. For example: budget to 18yo</description></item></channel></rss>