<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/</link><description>Recent content on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2024 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2024/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2024/</guid><description>​
Camping in snow capped Himalayas in Uttarakhand
All links are arranged by their chronologically descending order:
07/03/2024
Rich Indians India-1 (Top 1%), India-2 (Top 10%) are thriving, but India-3 (Rest) is not Sale of Luxury products is increasing but sale of mass products is not Most businesses are targeting India-2, ie top 10% earning capacity consumers Power Law Ecommerce is mostly driven from few pincodes Shark Tank businesses are targeting India-1, ie Top 1% These Top 1% can easily be equal to population of a European country, hence many international luxury brands are trying to enter India market Old Money, New Money (from Startup World) Income Tax Section 54F - People buy luxury apartments (limit is one) to save long term capital gain tax (later gov capped it to 10Cr) Business owners add their family members to Cap Table so that they can buy multiple properties Rise of Nouveau Rich - French word for people who have recently become rich and want to show off their money Why Dune was considered unadaptable terminology most dialogue are internal dialogues Add to that, it is written with third-person perspective omniscient.</description></item><item><title>2023 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2023/</guid><description>​
Camping in snow capped Himalayas in Uttarakhand
All links are arranged by their chronologically descending order:
31/12/2023
Saazish - poem by Javed Akhtar, #politics #humanity 26/12/2023
NM football group 20/12/2023
Wikipedia datasets Mistral LLM 17/12/2023
In India, call recording is legal if atleast one party is aware or gives consent to it. History of US currency&amp;rsquo;s domination 16/12/2023
Haridwar Man gives great advice on cleanliness Documentary on Dark web - Hunt for AlphaBay&amp;rsquo;s Owner 14/12/2023</description></item><item><title>Understanding and Embracing Introversion</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</guid><description>Introversion has been a popular term in the pop culture since the past few years. While there is a wealth of information and resources available on introversion, understanding and dealing with this trait can still feel overwhelming or confusing.
In this article, I aim to simplify and distill some of the key principles of introversion, and share few tips for living and working with this personality trait, I have learnt and come across.</description></item><item><title>'A Marriage Knot' By Shobana Mahadevan - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</guid><description>Thoughts Feel good book Classic love story, uses common tropes aunt is bad, uncle is good but helpless, mother-in-law is good and supportive the female lead gets saved by a prince (in terms of both qualities and riches) and she is looking for basic respect and freedom - classic damsel in distress the male lead gets pushed by the female lead and he acknowledges his responsibilities and finds his strength, he gets challenged by the female&amp;rsquo;s thought process and in turn keeps falling for her both complete each other, opposites attract (if both complement each other), which is the case here No strong conflict: Both (female and male leads) lack any negative trait, the resolution of their conflict is merely a conversation away - what they agreed upon and what they want now Captures Look dear.</description></item><item><title>Rules of Engagement in a Community</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</guid><description>​
Community culture has become increasingly popular in recent years due to the growing recognition of the importance of social connection and the power of collective action to effect change.
​
What is community? A community can be defined as a group of people who share a common interest, goal, or identity and come together to support each other, share ideas, and collaborate on projects or initiatives.
​
General engagement rules one should follow Every community has its own set of unspoken rules of engagement, which may vary depending on the nature of the community, its values, and the people who participate in it.</description></item><item><title>'Games People Play' By Eric Berne - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</guid><description>​
First published in the 1960s and recognized as a classic work of its kind by professionals, the bestselling &amp;lsquo;Games People Play&amp;rsquo; is also an accessible and fascinating read. It is a wise, original, witty and very sensible analysis of the games we play in order to live with one another and with ourselves.
Captures Chapter 1
the most favoured forms of stimuli are those provided by physical intimacy
In technical language, an ego state may be described phenomenologically as a coherent system of feelings, and operationally as a set of coherent behaviour patterns.</description></item><item><title>'Acko on AIR - Subrata Mitra, Abhinav Chaturvedi (Accel Partners)' with Varun</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</guid><description>​
Talk: Acko on AIR - Subrata, Abhinav (Accel Partners, Acko&amp;rsquo;s first investors) - at Acko townhall
Notes:
Anecdote by Abhinav - Sachin Bansal (his then colleague at Amazon) fixed code in amazon payment for which the team was struggling (system was crashing completely when running a test suite cos of which they were unable to launch) Flipkart initial investment by Subrata - 3.5 cr for 25% - everytime they would come they talk about something they fixed (everyday) - committed to the cause When looking for investment - references from networks matter (Accel will ask Varun for Acko&amp;rsquo;s employee) Why most startups fail get to some scale as quickly as possible (zero to one) not having sharp focus (anti of why win - having a sharp focus) team dynamics don&amp;rsquo;t workout, going out in different directions Advice to youngsters Abhinav, Subrata - work with really good people, it compounds (good mentor) Subrata - really enjoy working whatever you do Varun - stay with a team for long time (5yrs or so it takes to crack a market) - everything compounds - your skills, your market value, your networks (you don&amp;rsquo;t restart everytime) One trait which Abhinav looks for in early founders - mentally and physically fit - it is tough to maintain Acko vision - 10Bn dollar (by 2030), in market that compounds Make companies in bust (startup bubble, less distractions), they will come out on top (strong) when the market is out of bust, market cycle again starts (happened multiple times in past - 9/11, 2008 etc)</description></item><item><title>'Masters of Scale - Eric Schmidt with Reid Hoffman</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</guid><description>​
Eric Schmidt was Executive Chairman of Google’s parent company, Alphabet, Inc. From 2001 to 2011 he was CEO of Google. Previously, he was CEO of Novell and before that a long-time executive at Sun Microsystems.
Notes:
HOFFMAN: Amit eventually built a tool that accurately predicts how much revenue the company had at any given time, down to the second. Pranks and productivity tend to blend together at Google, which is why Eric doesn’t dwell on the question of why Amit moved in to begin with.</description></item><item><title>'The Ego and The Id' By Sigmund Freud - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Ego and the Id&amp;rdquo; (1923) is a prominent paper (also book) by Sigmund Freud, the founder of psychoanalysis.
The book formulates the structural personality model in which he articulates a map of the different layers which comprise the human soul: the conscious, unconscious and preconscious which correlate with the faculties of ego, id and super-ego.
Captures Chapter 1: Consciousness and What is Unconscious
‘Being conscious’ is in the first place a purely descriptive term, resting on perception of the most immediate and certain character.</description></item><item><title>शब्दों की कलम - verses 🎶</title><link>https://wilspi.com/verses/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/verses/</guid><description>These are mostly songs, checkout poems
​
Amitabh Bhattacharya Album: Lootera (2013) हवाओं से जो माँगा हिस्सा मेरा
तो बदले में हवा ने सांस दी
अकेलेपन से छेड़ी जब गुफ़्तगू
मेरे दिल ने आवाज़ दी
&amp;ndash; Zinda (Lootera)
​
Avicii True (2013) I tried carrying the weight of the world But I only have two hands
I hope I get the chance to travel the world
But I don&amp;rsquo;t have any plans</description></item><item><title>'The Liberation of Sita' By Volga - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</guid><description>Thoughts Does Ramayana qualify for a feminist fiction?
Post Ram and Sita&amp;rsquo;s homecoming, Sita was asked to give a chastity test, and she left the palace after proving herself. She could have left without undergoing the test but then the public would have indeed believed that she was at fault.
Whether Ramayana is based on true events or if it&amp;rsquo;s a fictional tale it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, in either case Sita&amp;rsquo;s character is liberating.</description></item><item><title>'The subtle art of not giving a fuck' By Mark Manson - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fuck/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-subtle-art-of-not-giving-a-fuck/</guid><description>Don&amp;rsquo;t try Comfort with yourself as a failure, the Bukowsky&amp;rsquo;s story Feedback loop from hell, thinking about what I am thinking, anxiety about being anxious, feel guilty for feeling guilty Backwards law: the desire for more positive experience is itself a negative experience. and, paradoxically, the acceptance of one&amp;rsquo;s negative experience is itself a positive experience Too many fucks to give. Exactly the way you want it to be. Sickness.</description></item><item><title>2022 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2022/</guid><description>​
29/12/2022
Computer Scientist explains Zero Knowledge Proof to 5 different aged people https://youtu.be/D1X5wi9NK9o?t=136 Why outlaws and villains (not necessary evils) have a larger fan following than the good-doers?
Hero (or a good-doer) is often confused with the problem of &amp;ldquo;to be or not to be&amp;rdquo;, while the villain does what he thinks, so the fan-following is tilted more towards the villain because confidence attracts. If the hero is not stuck in the &amp;ldquo;to be or not to be&amp;rdquo; zone and is clear and confident and acts on things and his beliefs quickly, he shall gets all the attraction.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>'Parasyte' By Hitoshi Iwaaki - Manga Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</guid><description>Parasyte is a manga/anime that deals on some pretty heavy subjects regarding the existence of humans.
Thoughts Are humans parasytes? Action Favourite Moments This scene in chapter-48, it was a powerful scene. The arc seems to complete here 🙏 Scene in Chapter-48</description></item><item><title>Intention Vs Impact - framework to prioritise yourself</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</guid><description>Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we retrospect, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
This is one way to analyse such a situation and find ways to move forward.
What is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Impact&amp;rdquo;? Whenever we are hurt by the other person&amp;rsquo;s action, and we try to confront the other person, they often don&amp;rsquo;t acknowledge the harm happened.</description></item><item><title>'Ghachar Ghochar' By Vivek Shanbhag - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</guid><description>A look into the lives of an Indian household with all its perjudices and beautiful memories.
Captures someone who simply sits there for so long must have a thousand wheels spinning in his head.
‘Sir – one story, many sides.’
Words after all are nothing by themselves. They burst into meaning only in the minds they’ve entered. At times, I’m tempted to unburden myself to him. But then, what’s the point when he seems to know without being told?</description></item><item><title>'Animal Farm' By George Orwell - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</guid><description>The book is a satire on Communism.
Fun Facts It was written between 1943 and 1945, and since Britain, US and Soviet Union had good relations, majority publication houses refused to publish the book. Summary Chapter 1:
After Mr. Jones, the owner of Manor Farm, falls asleep in a drunken stupor, all of his animals meet in the big barn at the request of old Major, a 12-year-old pig. Major delivers a rousing political speech about the evils inflicted upon them by their human keepers and their need to rebel against the tyranny of Man.</description></item><item><title>2021 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2021/</guid><description>​
04/11/2021
Dune https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_UM3Lhj9Ywk https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yhYU4ZbLmmk 22/09/2021
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83iZ68s-9YE Farm Laws India 2020 - Documentary https://dev.to/codesphere/should-i-use-sqlite-postgresql-or-mysql-1o4b 20/09/2021
https://moontowermeta.com/the-most-important-solutions-are-simple-just-not-easy/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmbSpTJXozk we hire products to do the job for us https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eJ07g2NtOiY decomplication: the art of first principles thinking www.paulgraham.com/mean.html meanness and success are inversely correlated (PG admits there might be selection bias here) for most of history success meant control of scarce resources this is changing, increasingly the games that matter are not zero-sum being mean makes you stupid, makes you fight, and in turn drains your energy mean founders struggle with hiring best people (since best people have better options and mean founders cant convince to join them) 03/09/2021</description></item><item><title>'The Count Of Monte Cristo' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</guid><description>In 2019, a colleague, with similar appetite as mine, recommended me to read &amp;lsquo;The Count of Monte Cristo&amp;rsquo; describing it as the best revenge story there is, and after deliberating on it for some time, I finally took the plunge.
The book is not yet complete, but will keep adding my thoughts and notes here.
Thoughts on the book Hard vocabulary - The book is from centuries back and people spoke and wrote in a different form.</description></item><item><title>'The Cathedral and The Bazaar' By Eric S. Raymond - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</guid><description>The Cathedral and the Bazaar (abbreviated CatB)
Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary is an essay, and later a book, by Eric S. Raymond
Focal points: Every good work of software starts by scratching a developer's personal itch. Too often software developers spend their days grinding away for pay at programs they neither need nor love To solve an interesting problem, start by finding a problem that is interesting to you.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Elm with 2048 game</title><link>https://wilspi.com/p/2048-game-in-elmlang/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 15:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/p/2048-game-in-elmlang/</guid><description>​
In this post I will be creating a small game, 2048 in Elm. 2048 is a game created by gabrielecirulli which went viral in 2014.
I chose 2048 because the game mechanics are simple which will help us understand Elm clearly. Also, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to make another todo app.
You can play here.
​
The Game Mechanics? There are some number tiles on the board (4x4). The number on the tile will be a power of 2 with minimum being 2.</description></item><item><title>'Experimenting with content' by Sattvik Mishra</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</guid><description> ​
Talk: Sattvik Mishra: Experimenting with content
Who: ScoopWhoop CEO
SOTS:
Traditional media houses prioritizes news for you (in a generic way, by giving more space on newspaper and time on tv-shows, also by ordering and grouping same genre together) News is subjective, for some it could be a spoiler in game of thrones, for others it could be sports. To create awareness on unconventional topics, make it relatable. For example: budget to 18yo</description></item><item><title>Save the production with Nginx hack</title><link>https://wilspi.com/p/save-production-via-nginx/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/p/save-production-via-nginx/</guid><description>​
Quick nginx hack to save your production web server in case the web service starts crashing.
If you have been working in a production environment, you know at certain times your web service can crash due to some unknown reason (code failure). It will take some time to do the RCA and fix the issue. A quick hack is to have multiple web services running on different ports resp. that can take the load off if any of them goes down.</description></item><item><title>'The Art of War' By Sun Tzu - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</guid><description>Summary Calculation When you encounter a conflict in your life, before you act, seek out a solitary place that balances and enhances your mind to spiritually think things through.
Face the conflict and pro-actively seek to understand what lies at its root. An enemy or adversary is someone who seeks to do you harm. You and your family no doubt have disagreements, but everyone works for the same goals. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to subdue those you love and care about; you want to support them.</description></item><item><title>2020 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2020/</guid><description>​
07/10/20
https://www.sidharthajha.com/blog/lky-dials-of-gov 06/10/20
The Cathedral and the Bazaar, summary 28/09/20
switch chess sides - good way to learn and understand the game from opposite perspective essay by Bhagat Singh Essay by Bhagat Singh 27/09/20
https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract Tesseract OCR Heartbleed, SSL vulnerability https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbleed https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortune_(Unix)#Purpose Fortune program https://www.notion.so/UrbanNazi-com-A-Social-Media-Report-for-Bot-Detection-9aab55d505dd43a7b74c96586d071432 Bots on Twitter -&amp;gt; Analysis from Indian context https://dogrilyrics.blogspot.com/2019/02/banku-deya-chachua.html Lyrics of Banu Deya Chachua, Dogri (Himachali?) folk song https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/04/19/einstein-curie-letter/ https://ferd.ca/the-zen-of-erlang.html https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c3Zga1wXaOk https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-ideas-farmers-protest-farm-bills-6612927/ Farmers protest https://www.</description></item><item><title>'Modern Romance' By Aziz Ansari - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</guid><description>Captures “People will go as far as they have to to find a mate, but no farther.”
For the young people who got married in the 1950s, getting married was the first step in adulthood. After high school or college, you got married and you left the house. For today’s folks, marriage is usually one of the later stages in adulthood. Now most young people spend their twenties and thirties in another stage of life, where they go to university, start a career, and experience being an adult outside of their parents’ home before marriage.</description></item><item><title>'Bhagavad Gita' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</guid><description>Translation by Winthrop Sargeant
Captures happiness and unhappiness are the same, is ready for immortality.
if you will not undertake this righteous war, thereupon, having avoided your own duty and glory, you shall incur evil.
Holding pleasure and pain to be alike, likewise gain and loss, victory and defeat then engage in battle! Thus you shall not incur evil.
be free from those three qualities, Arjuna, indifferent towards the pairs of opposites, eternally fixed in truth, free from thoughts of acquisition and comfort, and possessed of the Self.</description></item><item><title>About wilspi.com</title><link>https://wilspi.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/about/</guid><description>​
My name is Sourabh and welcome to my blog.
This digital repository serves as my personal learning project, enabling me to collect my thoughts, insights, notes, and understanding of diverse concepts, much like a traditional commonplace book. The concept of a commonplace book isn&amp;rsquo;t merely about accumulating knowledge; it&amp;rsquo;s a method of synthesis. It allows me to intertwine seemingly disparate ideas, creating a web of interconnected thoughts that contributes to a deeper understanding of the world.</description></item><item><title>Are you joking me?</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</guid><description>​
With the advent of Internet, the meme culture and standup comedy culture has blasted in the last few years.
Internet has not only enabled the reach via social networks,
People could try out different material not only cheaply but also with the ease of a click. The showoff of facebook check-ins and instagram stories have acted as catalyst in the expansion of the gig culture. Gags I found funny (likeness is subjective):</description></item><item><title>Cheatsheet for life ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</guid><description>You You are unique 🫶 Believe in yourself Leave every place/relationship (even family) that doesn&amp;rsquo;t value you. Love yourself. Believe in yourself. &amp;ldquo;Be gentle with yourself; show yourself the same kindness and patience you might show a young child - the child you once were. If you won&amp;rsquo;t be your own friend, who will be? If, when playing an opponent, you are also opposing yourself, you will be outnumbered.&amp;rdquo; Speak up You are the biggest spokesperson for yourself.</description></item><item><title>Learn Kannada Learn 🧑‍🎓️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</guid><description>Namaskaara 🙏
Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) namaskaara greetings These are notes created while learning Kannada, hope it helps. Navigate to common phrases, if you are looking for quick use.
Pronouns Nominative Pronouns Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) naanu I/me naavu We niivu You (with respect) ivaru He/She - This person (with respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaru He/She - That person (with respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) niinu You (without respect - singular) ivaLu She - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaLu She - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) ivanu He - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avanu He - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) Notes:</description></item><item><title>navigation map 🧭</title><link>https://wilspi.com/sitelinks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/sitelinks/</guid><description>book notes
​ words ✍️
opinions
shower thoughts
old posts
musings
🔗 link-log
✍️ mantras
simple pleasures
tag cloud
watched/watchlist
learn kannada</description></item><item><title>opinions</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</guid><description>Generally anything mainstream is cringe
Alcohol is considered bad because it causes one to lose control over senses. Anything that causes one to lose control over their senses is bad.
Golden rule of partying. One party Two Drinks Main purpose is Socialising. It’s a platform to meet people and make new friends not to get drunk. The loss of bodily control that comes with alcohol or drugs is fun. Do it, but within the confines of a controlled, safe environment where you are not likely to do anything you&amp;rsquo;ll regret when you have regained control.</description></item><item><title>Political Ideologies</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/political-ideologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/political-ideologies/</guid><description>Political Ideologies Conservatism Tries to &amp;ldquo;conserve&amp;rdquo; traditional value In western countries, conservatives usually promote nuclear family organised religion military property rights Liberalism Dominant ideology in modern history Promotes individual rights people approved government equality before the law free market</description></item><item><title>principles 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/principles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/principles/</guid><description>decluttering
deleting old stuff giving up old things/thoughts simple living / minimalistic</description></item><item><title>product sketches</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/product-sketches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/product-sketches/</guid><description>​
Product Ideas Community Radio - Listen with me A radio where the host can play songs from spotify and everyone can join and listen to the songs and react in real time.
Timeless Party and Reactions - watch with me You watch videos and you want to share with your closed ones, and watch with them. If you can store the reaction video sec by sec and plan watching with the reaction video.</description></item><item><title>reviews 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/reviews/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/reviews/</guid><description>Movies watched/ing: wilspi
Web-Series/Shows watched/ing: wilspi
This page is archived.</description></item><item><title>shower-thoughts 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</guid><description>2024-01-28
People mirror you, if you put out strong opinions, they do too. Does this happen when people admire you? they mirror you? To some extent, yes. They may seek to validate themselves in your eyes, thus emulating your actions. ~2024
Dating on apps is like doing crowdwork, asking what you do, why is a horse in your photo etc. 2023-11-23
Whitewash Image - PR masterstroke - Start the anti-bullying campaign to cover up being the bully in the past.</description></item><item><title>simple pleasures</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/simple-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/simple-pleasures/</guid><description>Clean Sheets
Coming home and the feeling of getting into bed with clean sheets after the shower Hearing a song that you haven&amp;rsquo;t thought of in a while
First cup of chai in the morning
A hot bath
Going on a walk or ride with soft sun and cool breeze</description></item><item><title>thought experiments 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</guid><description>Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we live in Fantasy world? https://www.reddit.com/r/Buddhism/comments/x2mk3f/why_we_shouldnt_live_in_a_fantasy/
What is Spirit/Soul? What are the properties of it? If it&amp;rsquo;s not physical, lets say you get a brain injury, is your soul the same? your personality comes out differently after that. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it affect your soul?
What is consciousness?</description></item><item><title>travel checklist ✈️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/travel-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/travel-checklist/</guid><description>​
Pre-travel checklist Download music on mobile (network unavailablility preparedness) Mobile recharge (talktime, internet), check and confirm availability of network Charge every device (electricity) Make credit card payments Cash in hand ATM cards and pins Necessary printouts (if required) Booking tickets (stay, travelling, if required) Research itineraries (local) Packing ​
Things to carry Hike/Travel:
snacks (eatery) snickers dry fruits glucose small bag (quechua) sleeping eye cover neck pillow water bottle hygiene, skincare sunscreen brush and small toothpaste hand soap tissue roll lip balm hand sanitizer small towel gadgets power bank camera headphones clothing/accessories sunglasses/cap medicines crocin (fever/bodyache) loperamide (diarrhoea/loose motions) saradon (headache) ondem (vomiting/motion sickness) levocet (running nose) moov spray (pain relief spray) bandaides ​</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</guid><description>Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company
&amp;ldquo;The capacity to be alone is the capacity to love.
It may look paradoxical to you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. It is an existential truth: only those people who are capable of being alone are capable of love, of sharing, of going into the deepest core of another person&amp;ndash;without possessing the other, without becoming dependent on the other, without reducing the other to a thing, and without becoming addicted to the other.</description></item></channel></rss>