<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>link-log 🔗 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/</link><description>Recent content in link-log 🔗 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/link-log/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2023 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2023/</guid><description>​
Camping
24/10/2023
Vishal Bhardwaj - Samdish interview On a spiritual level, Khajuraho temple has naked sculputres all around its temple and nothing inside - this tells us to go within, to find yourself. People have psychology that when they praise someone, they want that person to fail the next time, to call him/her one time wonder and humanise him/her. Youtubers delete their comments (ok, yeah known thing). People often forget while browsing and check top few comments and get influenced by other&amp;rsquo;s opinions, so youtubers make sure they delete top comments which are reflect badly for them.</description></item><item><title>2022 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2022/</guid><description>​
29/12/2022
Computer Scientist explains Zero Knowledge Proof to 5 different aged people https://youtu.be/D1X5wi9NK9o?t=136 Why outlaws and villains (not necessary evils) have a larger fan following than the good-doers?
Hero (or a good-doer) is often confused with the problem of &amp;ldquo;to be or not to be&amp;rdquo;, while the villain does what he thinks, so the fan-following is tilted more towards the villain because confidence attracts. If the hero is not stuck in the &amp;ldquo;to be or not to be&amp;rdquo; zone and is clear and confident and acts on things and his beliefs quickly, he shall gets all the attraction.</description></item><item><title>2021 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2021/</guid><description>​
04/11/2021
Dune https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_UM3Lhj9Ywk https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yhYU4ZbLmmk 22/09/2021
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=83iZ68s-9YE Farm Laws India 2020 - Documentary https://dev.to/codesphere/should-i-use-sqlite-postgresql-or-mysql-1o4b 20/09/2021
https://moontowermeta.com/the-most-important-solutions-are-simple-just-not-easy/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VmbSpTJXozk we hire products to do the job for us https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eJ07g2NtOiY decomplication: the art of first principles thinking www.paulgraham.com/mean.html meanness and success are inversely correlated (PG admits there might be selection bias here) for most of history success meant control of scarce resources this is changing, increasingly the games that matter are not zero-sum being mean makes you stupid, makes you fight, and in turn drains your energy mean founders struggle with hiring best people (since best people have better options and mean founders cant convince to join them) 03/09/2021</description></item><item><title>2020 🔗</title><link>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/link-log/2020/</guid><description>​
07/10/20
https://www.sidharthajha.com/blog/lky-dials-of-gov 06/10/20
The Cathedral and the Bazaar, summary 28/09/20
switch chess sides - good way to learn and understand the game from opposite perspective essay by Bhagat Singh Essay by Bhagat Singh 27/09/20
https://github.com/tesseract-ocr/tesseract Tesseract OCR Heartbleed, SSL vulnerability https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heartbleed https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fortune_(Unix)#Purpose Fortune program https://www.notion.so/UrbanNazi-com-A-Social-Media-Report-for-Bot-Detection-9aab55d505dd43a7b74c96586d071432 Bots on Twitter -&amp;gt; Analysis from Indian context https://dogrilyrics.blogspot.com/2019/02/banku-deya-chachua.html Lyrics of Banu Deya Chachua, Dogri (Himachali?) folk song https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/04/19/einstein-curie-letter/ https://ferd.ca/the-zen-of-erlang.html https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c3Zga1wXaOk https://indianexpress.com/article/explained/explained-ideas-farmers-protest-farm-bills-6612927/ Farmers protest https://www.</description></item></channel></rss>