<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>romance on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/romance/</link><description>Recent content in romance on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/romance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'A Marriage Knot' By Shobana Mahadevan - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</guid><description>Thoughts Feel good book Classic love story, uses common tropes aunt is bad, uncle is good but helpless, mother-in-law is good and supportive the female lead gets saved by a prince (in terms of both qualities and riches) and she is looking for basic respect and freedom - classic damsel in distress the male lead gets pushed by the female lead and he acknowledges his responsibilities and finds his strength, he gets challenged by the female&amp;rsquo;s thought process and in turn keeps falling for her both complete each other, opposites attract (if both complement each other), which is the case here No strong conflict: Both (female and male leads) lack any negative trait, the resolution of their conflict is merely a conversation away - what they agreed upon and what they want now Captures Look dear.</description></item><item><title>'Modern Romance' By Aziz Ansari - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</guid><description>Captures “People will go as far as they have to to find a mate, but no farther.”
For the young people who got married in the 1950s, getting married was the first step in adulthood. After high school or college, you got married and you left the house. For today’s folks, marriage is usually one of the later stages in adulthood. Now most young people spend their twenties and thirties in another stage of life, where they go to university, start a career, and experience being an adult outside of their parents’ home before marriage.</description></item></channel></rss>