<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reviews 🔗 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/</link><description>Recent content in reviews 🔗 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Spiderman - Across the Spiderverse - notes and review</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/spiderman-across-the-spiderverse-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/spiderman-across-the-spiderverse-2023/</guid><description>Thoughts Brilliant movie What spectacular visuals, that&amp;rsquo;s called an experience Storytelling at point Loved the screenplay Nice soundtracks</description></item><item><title>Evil Dead Rise - notes and review</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/evil-dead-rise-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/evil-dead-rise-2023/</guid><description>Note: Spoilers Ahead
My Thoughts: This was fifth installation of the &amp;ldquo;Evil Dead&amp;rdquo; series, though I don&amp;rsquo;t remember watching the previous installations, yet this felt like a stand-alone movie (not sure if there was some backstory to it) There is only &amp;ldquo;Book of Dead&amp;rdquo; concept. I watched this in theatre and this was my first theatre experience of watching any horror/gore movie. Not sure if this happens for the horror genre, but some of the horror scenes became a laughter riot for the audience.</description></item><item><title>Guardians of the Galaxy - Vol. 3 - notes and review</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3-2023/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/guardians-of-the-galaxy-vol-3-2023/</guid><description>Note: Spoilers Ahead
Thoughts This movie is worth watching in theatre (prefer 3d), what a visual spectacle. Amazing visuals, good soundtracks, good world building. Story was okayish - not bad, not good, doable.</description></item><item><title>Decision to Leave - notes and review</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/decision-to-leave-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/decision-to-leave-2022/</guid><description>Note: Spoilers Ahead
Thoughts Good romantic thriller, beautiful visuals, good editing. Full of metaphors Thought provoking, you take it with you after the movie ends. &amp;ldquo;The moment you said you loved me, your love was over. The moment your love ended, my love began.&amp;rdquo; The highest form of love is sacrifice. Good afterwatch reads: https://mubi.com/notebook/posts/what-i-learned-translating-decision-to-leave https://www.reddit.com/r/TrueFilm/comments/zysqih/i_watched_decision_to_leave_and_here_are_my/ The film is flushed with poetic lines. The Monday Grandma says &amp;ldquo;I pray on Fridays for Mondays to come quickly (indicating she likes Song Seo Rae who takes care of her on Mondays) but sometimes Mondays come faster&amp;rdquo; - an allegory to her rapidly approaching death.</description></item><item><title>Not Okay - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/not-okay-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/not-okay-2022/</guid><description>This is a
It showed that while she has a lot of work ahead, she&amp;rsquo;s at least taken a step of putting other people before herself and seeing things from a point of view that isn&amp;rsquo;t her own.
Good looking protagonist making us empathize with her (we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t)
How she became a good writer? How come she was good at socialising later? And her attitude damn well changed. In general, the arc of the protagonist looks like</description></item><item><title>Triangle of Sadness - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/triangle-of-sadness-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/triangle-of-sadness-2022/</guid><description>Observations and Thoughts The movie talks about various philosophical topics Social Status Feminism Communism Many of the conflicts were closed too soon, the feminism topic Yaya quickly accepted the money part (she didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay), her reason was shallow saying she was testing if the other person can pay for after-marriage expenses like baby delivery etc. this was never recalled in the story later I liked exploring the philosophical topics I found the ending of Part-2, the discussion b/w Captain and Dimitry quite boring and worthless What was the point of those quotes or the complete shit show?</description></item><item><title>The Menu - notes and review</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/the-menu-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/the-menu-2022/</guid><description>Note: Spoilers Ahead
Thoughts</description></item><item><title>Raincoat - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/raincoat-2004/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/raincoat-2004/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Glass Onion - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/glass-onion-2022/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/glass-onion-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Avatar 2 - review | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/avatar-2-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/avatar-2-2022/</guid><description>Thoughts Beautiful visuals and screenplay Imax 3d was a treat Average story I went for the imax experience (pre-booked in way advance). I felt the ticket was too costly, though I went for it because I didnt want to miss the theatre experience of Avatar, given I missed it for the previous part. The experience was average because we had seen all the different elements of the Pandora world, even the story felt dull because it was retelling of the same previous story, the change was water.</description></item><item><title>Black Panther - Wakanda Forever - review | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/black-panther-2-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/black-panther-2-2022/</guid><description>Thoughts Good Marvel movie after a while. Feminism: Good mix of Feminism which was not overly done. The women in the movie are never considered below or seem to be targeting men, a real equality. Black: The movie is just Black people, even the student scientist was black too. Isn&amp;rsquo;t this racist in a way? It has all the elements of an &amp;ldquo;Origin&amp;rdquo; story (it is an Origin story in a way for the lady Panther).</description></item><item><title>Kantara - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/kantara-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/kantara-2022/</guid><description>Thoughts
What a brilliant movie, such amalgamation of culture, story, socio-political issues. All kudos to writing and screenplay. The basic story is very common trope, connecting it to the culture (which is new to everyone) was the key. The story didn;t go overboard with the mythology part, it was all believable and realistic. Fantastically told story. The demigod connecting the bridges between man (protagonist) and the nature (forest officer). The story didn&amp;rsquo;t have much of twists and turns, but still kept me hooked.</description></item><item><title>Top Gun Maverick - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/top-gun-maverick-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/top-gun-maverick-2022/</guid><description>I recently watched Top Gun and was not sure if this movie can offer anything more (with Tom Cruise in lead), probably more training and fighting jet sequences. Oh boy I was in for a ride. This was a new chapter with the same characters, and the writers connected it all so well. It was a continuation. After 30min, audience knew where the story would go, but the pace of the movie kept changing, the twists were good.</description></item><item><title>I saw the Devil - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/i-saw-the-devil-2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/i-saw-the-devil-2010/</guid><description> I rewatched this movie recently, the movie is a classic gore movie.</description></item><item><title>Chup - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/chup-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/chup-2022/</guid><description>Thoughts Great movie. No drama,</description></item><item><title>Everything Everywhere All At Once - my thoughts | wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/reviews/everything-everywhere-all-at-once-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/reviews/everything-everywhere-all-at-once-2022/</guid><description> The screenplay, the visuals, the merging of different universes was brilliantly done. The characterisation was good. The crux of the story is simple and straightforward, Need to rewatch to understand the philosophical pov.</description></item></channel></rss>