<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wisdom on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/wisdom/</link><description>Recent content in wisdom on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>beautiful quotes 🙌</title><link>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</guid><description>​
Impatience with actions, patience with results.
&amp;ndash; Naval
​
Your heart needs to break multiple times for it to open up.
&amp;ndash; Rumi
​
And those who were seen dancing were thought to be insane by those who could not hear the music.
&amp;ndash; Friedrich Nietzsche
​
Somewhere in the process of maturing into adults, most humans misunderstood comfort for happiness.
​
Alice came to a fork in the road.</description></item><item><title>Life Mantras ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</guid><description>Advices You are unique 🫶 Leave every place/ relationship that doesn&amp;rsquo;t value you. Love yourself. Believe in yourself. Speak up. Your opinion matters. You miss out on 100% of things if you don't ask for things/ put forth your opinions. Speaking up brings that probability to 50-50. Your opinions are different and you need to embrace them. Everything about you, that you think is &amp;ldquo;weird&amp;rdquo; is actually your biggest strength because it makes you different in a sea of people.</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</guid><description>Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company Anger memory of pain in the past messenger that shows you that something important to you is being betrayed, squashed, or overlooked. A boundary, a value, a desire. Don&amp;rsquo;t kill (supress) that messenger (ofcourse don&amp;rsquo;t react). best remedy is to delay (any reaction) understand the source, when you get irritated, write and explain the feelings, it might help in identifying the source &amp;ldquo;The opposite of anger is not calmness, its empathy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Mehmet Oz Anxiety worry about something that has typically yet to happen (future) guilt causes anxiety (eg: lying, procrastination) body&amp;rsquo;s natural response to stress Anxiety is not having clarity about what is within one&amp;rsquo;s control and what is outside of one&amp;rsquo;s control - partially correct?</description></item></channel></rss>