<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>wisdom on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/wisdom/</link><description>Recent content in wisdom on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/wisdom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>cheatsheet for life ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</guid><description>You are unique 🫶 Believe in yourself We have all got a little bit of &amp;lsquo;save the world&amp;rsquo; in us. It&amp;rsquo;s ok if you only save one person, and it&amp;rsquo;s ok if that person is you.
Leave every place/relationship (even family) that doesn&amp;rsquo;t value you. Love yourself. Believe in yourself.
&amp;ldquo;Be gentle with yourself; show yourself the same kindness and patience you might show a young child - the child you once were.</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</guid><description>Addiction How Addiction Happens: Ingredients Lot to cope with Who am I? What is my identity? Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company
&amp;ldquo;The capacity to be alone is the capacity to love.
It may look paradoxical to you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. It is an existential truth: only those people who are capable of being alone are capable of love, of sharing, of going into the deepest core of another person&amp;ndash;without possessing the other, without becoming dependent on the other, without reducing the other to a thing, and without becoming addicted to the other.</description></item></channel></rss>