<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>musings 💭 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/musings/</link><description>Recent content in musings 💭 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>Intention Vs Impact - framework to prioritise yourself</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</guid><description>Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we retrospect, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
This is one way to analyse such a situation and find ways to move forward.
What is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Impact&amp;rdquo;? Whenever we are hurt by the other person&amp;rsquo;s action, and we try to confront the other person, they often don&amp;rsquo;t acknowledge the harm happened.</description></item><item><title>Cheatsheet for life ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</guid><description>You You are unique 🫶 Believe in yourself Leave every place/relationship (even family) that doesn&amp;rsquo;t value you. Love yourself. Believe in yourself. &amp;ldquo;Be gentle with yourself; show yourself the same kindness and patience you might show a young child - the child you once were. If you won&amp;rsquo;t be your own friend, who will be? If, when playing an opponent, you are also opposing yourself, you will be outnumbered.&amp;rdquo; Speak up You are the biggest spokesperson for yourself.</description></item><item><title>opinions</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</guid><description>Generally anything mainstream is cringe
Alcohol is considered bad because it causes one to lose control over senses. Anything that causes one to lose control over their senses is bad.
Golden rule of partying. One party Two Drinks Main purpose is Socialising. It’s a platform to meet people and make new friends not to get drunk. The loss of bodily control that comes with alcohol or drugs is fun. Do it, but within the confines of a controlled, safe environment where you are not likely to do anything you&amp;rsquo;ll regret when you have regained control.</description></item><item><title>shower-thoughts 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</guid><description>2024-01-28
People mirror you, if you put out strong opinions, they do too. Does this happen when people like you? they mirror you? In a way, yes, they want to prove themselves in the eyes of the opposite person. They do that. Dating on apps is like doing crowdwork, asking what you do, why is a horse in your photo etc. ~2024
I come from the India where A Hindu has to prove his secularism and a Musim has to prove his nationalism constantly.</description></item><item><title>simple pleasures</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/simple-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/simple-pleasures/</guid><description>Clean Sheets
Coming home and the feeling of getting into bed with clean sheets after the shower Hearing a song that you haven&amp;rsquo;t thought of in a while
First cup of chai in the morning
A hot bath
Going on a walk or ride with soft sun and cool breeze</description></item><item><title>thought experiments 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</guid><description>Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we live in Fantasy world? https://www.reddit.com/r/Buddhism/comments/x2mk3f/why_we_shouldnt_live_in_a_fantasy/
What is Spirit/Soul? What are the properties of it? If it&amp;rsquo;s not physical, lets say you get a brain injury, is your soul the same? your personality comes out differently after that. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it affect your soul?
What is consciousness?</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</guid><description>Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company
&amp;ldquo;The capacity to be alone is the capacity to love.
It may look paradoxical to you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. It is an existential truth: only those people who are capable of being alone are capable of love, of sharing, of going into the deepest core of another person&amp;ndash;without possessing the other, without becoming dependent on the other, without reducing the other to a thing, and without becoming addicted to the other.</description></item></channel></rss>