<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>musings 💭 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/musings/</link><description>Recent content in musings 💭 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intention Vs Action - framework to prioritise yourself</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-action/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-action/</guid><description>​
Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
There are frameworks to better understand and analyse your/others&amp;rsquo; actions, one such framework that has helped me to judge these situations is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Action&amp;rdquo;.
​
Why Intention Vs Action?</description></item><item><title>shower-thoughts 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/shower-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/shower-thoughts/</guid><description>[2023-03-31] Movies in general use good looking people to sell their story. It is a visual medium afterall. ​* [2022-10-22] * &amp;ldquo;Save for Later&amp;rdquo; - Are we becoming collective procastinators? Save this article for later -&amp;gt; Pockets, One-tab, Reddit-save, Twitter-Bookmark, all these apps/features are building procastination in us. How many of us go back to that saved thread or article?
~timeline(NA) Indian traffic behaves how sediments behave in the water, gravitationally pulled towards the signal.</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/words/</guid><description>​
Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company ​
Anger memory of pain in the past messenger that shows you that something important to you is being betrayed, squashed, or overlooked. A boundary, a value, a desire. Don&amp;rsquo;t kill (supress) that messenger (ofcourse don&amp;rsquo;t react). best remedy is to delay (any reaction) understand the source, when you get irritated, write and explain the feelings, it might help in identifying the source &amp;ldquo;The opposite of anger is not calmness, its empathy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Mehmet Oz ​</description></item></channel></rss>