<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>philosophy on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in philosophy on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'The Ego and The Id' By Sigmund Freud - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Ego and the Id&amp;rdquo; (1923) is a prominent paper (also book) by Sigmund Freud, the founder of psychoanalysis.
The book formulates the structural personality model in which he articulates a map of the different layers which comprise the human soul: the conscious, unconscious and preconscious which correlate with the faculties of ego, id and super-ego.
Captures Chapter 1: Consciousness and What is Unconscious
‘Being conscious’ is in the first place a purely descriptive term, resting on perception of the most immediate and certain character.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>Intention Vs Impact - framework to prioritise yourself</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-impact/</guid><description>Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we retrospect, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
This is one way to analyse such a situation and find ways to bring more accountability.
What is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Impact&amp;rdquo;? Whenever we are hurt by the other person&amp;rsquo;s action, and we try to confront the other person, they often don&amp;rsquo;t acknowledge the harm happened.</description></item><item><title>'The Art of War' By Sun Tzu - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</guid><description>Summary Calculation When you encounter a conflict in your life, before you act, seek out a solitary place that balances and enhances your mind to spiritually think things through.
Face the conflict and pro-actively seek to understand what lies at its root. An enemy or adversary is someone who seeks to do you harm. You and your family no doubt have disagreements, but everyone works for the same goals. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to subdue those you love and care about; you want to support them.</description></item><item><title>'Bhagavad Gita' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</guid><description>Translation by Winthrop Sargeant
Captures happiness and unhappiness are the same, is ready for immortality.
if you will not undertake this righteous war, thereupon, having avoided your own duty and glory, you shall incur evil.
Holding pleasure and pain to be alike, likewise gain and loss, victory and defeat then engage in battle! Thus you shall not incur evil.
be free from those three qualities, Arjuna, indifferent towards the pairs of opposites, eternally fixed in truth, free from thoughts of acquisition and comfort, and possessed of the Self.</description></item><item><title>cheatsheet for life ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/mantras/</guid><description>You are unique 🫶 Believe in yourself We have all got a little bit of &amp;lsquo;save the world&amp;rsquo; in us. It&amp;rsquo;s ok if you only save one person, and it&amp;rsquo;s ok if that person is you.
Leave every place/relationship that doesn&amp;rsquo;t value you. Love yourself. Believe in yourself.
&amp;ldquo;Be gentle with yourself; show yourself the same kindness and patience you might show a young child - the child you once were.</description></item><item><title>Political Ideologies</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/political-ideologies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/political-ideologies/</guid><description>Political Ideologies Conservatism Tries to &amp;ldquo;conserve&amp;rdquo; traditional value In western countries, conservatives usually promote nuclear family organised religion military property rights Liberalism Dominant ideology in modern history Promotes individual rights people approved government equality before the law free market</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/words/</guid><description>Addiction How Addiction Happens: Ingredients Lot to cope with Who am I? What is my identity? Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company
&amp;ldquo;The capacity to be alone is the capacity to love.
It may look paradoxical to you, but it&amp;rsquo;s not. It is an existential truth: only those people who are capable of being alone are capable of love, of sharing, of going into the deepest core of another person&amp;ndash;without possessing the other, without becoming dependent on the other, without reducing the other to a thing, and without becoming addicted to the other.</description></item></channel></rss>