<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on wilspi | Sourabh</title>
    <link>https://wilspi.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on wilspi | Sourabh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Seven Deadly Sins</title>
      <link>https://wilspi.com/post/musing/7-deadly-sins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wilspi.com/post/musing/7-deadly-sins/</guid>
      <description>The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intention Vs Action - tool to prioritise yourself</title>
      <link>https://wilspi.com/post/musing/intention-vs-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wilspi.com/post/musing/intention-vs-action/</guid>
      <description>​
Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
There are tools to better understand and analyse your/others&#39; actions, one such tool that has helped me to judge these situations is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Action&amp;rdquo;.
​
Whenever there is a conflict in your life and if you confront the other person, they often don&amp;rsquo;t acknowledge the harm happened.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
