<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes 📄 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes 📄 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding and Embracing Introversion</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</guid><description>Introversion has been a popular term in the pop culture since the past few years. While there is a wealth of information and resources available on introversion, understanding and dealing with this trait can still feel overwhelming or confusing.
In this article, I aim to simplify and distill some of the key principles of introversion, and share few tips for living and working with this personality trait, I have learnt and come across.</description></item><item><title>Rules of Engagement in a Community</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</guid><description>​
Community culture has become increasingly popular in recent years due to the growing recognition of the importance of social connection and the power of collective action to effect change.
​
What is community? A community can be defined as a group of people who share a common interest, goal, or identity and come together to support each other, share ideas, and collaborate on projects or initiatives.
​
General engagement rules one should follow Every community has its own set of unspoken rules of engagement, which may vary depending on the nature of the community, its values, and the people who participate in it.</description></item><item><title>'Games People Play' By Eric Berne - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</guid><description>​
First published in the 1960s and recognized as a classic work of its kind by professionals, the bestselling &amp;lsquo;Games People Play&amp;rsquo; is also an accessible and fascinating read. It is a wise, original, witty and very sensible analysis of the games we play in order to live with one another and with ourselves.
Captures Chapter 1
the most favoured forms of stimuli are those provided by physical intimacy
In technical language, an ego state may be described phenomenologically as a coherent system of feelings, and operationally as a set of coherent behaviour patterns.</description></item><item><title>'Acko on AIR - Subrata Mitra, Abhinav Chaturvedi (Accel Partners)' with Varun</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</guid><description>​
Talk: Acko on AIR - Subrata, Abhinav (Accel Partners, Acko&amp;rsquo;s first investors) - at Acko townhall
Notes:
Anecdote by Abhinav - Sachin Bansal (his then colleague at Amazon) fixed code in amazon payment for which the team was struggling (system was crashing completely when running a test suite cos of which they were unable to launch) Flipkart initial investment by Subrata - 3.5 cr for 25% - everytime they would come they talk about something they fixed (everyday) - committed to the cause When looking for investment - references from networks matter (Accel will ask Varun for Acko&amp;rsquo;s employee) Why most startups fail get to some scale as quickly as possible (zero to one) not having sharp focus (anti of why win - having a sharp focus) team dynamics don&amp;rsquo;t workout, going out in different directions Advice to youngsters Abhinav, Subrata - work with really good people, it compounds (good mentor) Subrata - really enjoy working whatever you do Varun - stay with a team for long time (5yrs or so it takes to crack a market) - everything compounds - your skills, your market value, your networks (you don&amp;rsquo;t restart everytime) One trait which Abhinav looks for in early founders - mentally and physically fit - it is tough to maintain Acko vision - 10Bn dollar (by 2030), in market that compounds Make companies in bust (startup bubble, less distractions), they will come out on top (strong) when the market is out of bust, market cycle again starts (happened multiple times in past - 9/11, 2008 etc)</description></item><item><title>'Masters of Scale - Eric Schmidt with Reid Hoffman</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</guid><description>​
Eric Schmidt was Executive Chairman of Google’s parent company, Alphabet, Inc. From 2001 to 2011 he was CEO of Google. Previously, he was CEO of Novell and before that a long-time executive at Sun Microsystems.
Notes:
HOFFMAN: Amit eventually built a tool that accurately predicts how much revenue the company had at any given time, down to the second. Pranks and productivity tend to blend together at Google, which is why Eric doesn’t dwell on the question of why Amit moved in to begin with.</description></item><item><title>'The Ego and The Id' By Sigmund Freud - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</guid><description>​
&amp;ldquo;The Ego and the Id&amp;rdquo; (1923) is a prominent paper (also book) by Sigmund Freud, the founder of psychoanalysis.
The book formulates the structural personality model in which he articulates a map of the different layers which comprise the human soul: the conscious, unconscious and preconscious which correlate with the faculties of ego, id and super-ego.
​
Captures Chapter 1: Consciousness and What is Unconscious
‘Being conscious’ is in the first place a purely descriptive term, resting on perception of the most immediate and certain character.</description></item><item><title>'The Liberation of Sita' By Volga - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</guid><description>​
Thoughts Does Ramayana qualify for a feminist fiction?
Post Ram and Sita&amp;rsquo;s homecoming, Sita was asked to give a chastity test, and she left the palace after proving herself. She could have left without undergoing the test but then the public would have indeed believed that she was at fault.
Whether Ramayana is based on true events or if it&amp;rsquo;s a fictional tale it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, in either case Sita&amp;rsquo;s character is liberating.</description></item><item><title>'Parasyte' By Hitoshi Iwaaki - Manga Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</guid><description>Parasyte is a manga/anime that deals on some pretty heavy subjects regarding the existence of humans.
Thoughts Are humans parasytes? Action Favourite Moments This scene in chapter-48, it was a powerful scene. The arc seems to complete here 🙏 Scene in Chapter-48</description></item><item><title>'Ghachar Ghochar' By Vivek Shanbhag - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</guid><description>A look into the lives of an Indian household with all its perjudices and beautiful memories.
Captures someone who simply sits there for so long must have a thousand wheels spinning in his head.
‘Sir – one story, many sides.’
Words after all are nothing by themselves. They burst into meaning only in the minds they’ve entered. At times, I’m tempted to unburden myself to him. But then, what’s the point when he seems to know without being told?</description></item><item><title>'Animal Farm' By George Orwell - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</guid><description>The book is a satire on Communism.
Fun Facts It was written between 1943 and 1945, and since Britain, US and Soviet Union had good relations, majority publication houses refused to publish the book. Summary Chapter 1:
After Mr. Jones, the owner of Manor Farm, falls asleep in a drunken stupor, all of his animals meet in the big barn at the request of old Major, a 12-year-old pig. Major delivers a rousing political speech about the evils inflicted upon them by their human keepers and their need to rebel against the tyranny of Man.</description></item><item><title>'The Count Of Monte Cristo' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</guid><description>​
In 2019, a colleague, with similar appetite as mine, recommended me to read &amp;lsquo;The Count of Monte Cristo&amp;rsquo; describing it as the best revenge story there is, and after deliberating on it for some time, I finally took the plunge.
The book is not yet complete, but will keep adding my thoughts and notes here.
​
Thoughts on the book Hard vocabulary - The book is from centuries back and people spoke and wrote in a different form.</description></item><item><title>'The Cathedral and The Bazaar' By Eric S. Raymond - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</guid><description>​
The Cathedral and the Bazaar (abbreviated CatB)
Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary is an essay, and later a book, by Eric S. Raymond
​
Focal points: Every good work of software starts by scratching a developer's personal itch. Too often software developers spend their days grinding away for pay at programs they neither need nor love To solve an interesting problem, start by finding a problem that is interesting to you.</description></item><item><title>'Experimenting with content' by Sattvik Mishra</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</guid><description> ​
Talk: Sattvik Mishra: Experimenting with content
Who: ScoopWhoop CEO
SOTS:
Traditional media houses prioritizes news for you (in a generic way, by giving more space on newspaper and time on tv-shows, also by ordering and grouping same genre together) News is subjective, for some it could be a spoiler in game of thrones, for others it could be sports. To create awareness on unconventional topics, make it relatable. For example: budget to 18yo</description></item><item><title>'The Art of War' By Sun Tzu - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</guid><description>​
Summary Calculation When you encounter a conflict in your life, before you act, seek out a solitary place that balances and enhances your mind to spiritually think things through.
Face the conflict and pro-actively seek to understand what lies at its root. An enemy or adversary is someone who seeks to do you harm. You and your family no doubt have disagreements, but everyone works for the same goals. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to subdue those you love and care about; you want to support them.</description></item><item><title>'Modern Romance' By Aziz Ansari - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</guid><description>Captures “People will go as far as they have to to find a mate, but no farther.”
For the young people who got married in the 1950s, getting married was the first step in adulthood. After high school or college, you got married and you left the house. For today’s folks, marriage is usually one of the later stages in adulthood. Now most young people spend their twenties and thirties in another stage of life, where they go to university, start a career, and experience being an adult outside of their parents’ home before marriage.</description></item><item><title>'Bhagavad Gita' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</guid><description>Translation by Winthrop Sargeant
Captures happiness and unhappiness are the same, is ready for immortality.
if you will not undertake this righteous war, thereupon, having avoided your own duty and glory, you shall incur evil.
Holding pleasure and pain to be alike, likewise gain and loss, victory and defeat then engage in battle! Thus you shall not incur evil.
be free from those three qualities, Arjuna, indifferent towards the pairs of opposites, eternally fixed in truth, free from thoughts of acquisition and comfort, and possessed of the Self.</description></item><item><title>Are you joking me?</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</guid><description>​
With the advent of Internet, the meme culture and standup comedy culture has blasted in the last few years.
Internet has not only enabled the reach via social networks,
People could try out different material not only cheaply but also with the ease of a click. The showoff of facebook check-ins and instagram stories have acted as catalyst in the expansion of the gig culture. Gags I found funny (likeness is subjective):</description></item><item><title>beautiful quotes 🙌</title><link>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</guid><description>​
Impatience with actions, patience with results.
&amp;ndash; Naval
​
Your heart needs to break multiple times for it to open up.
&amp;ndash; Rumi
​
And those who were seen dancing were thought to be insane by those who could not hear the music.
&amp;ndash; Friedrich Nietzsche
​
Somewhere in the process of maturing into adults, most humans misunderstood comfort for happiness.
​
Alice came to a fork in the road.</description></item><item><title>Learning Kannada Language ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</guid><description>Namaskaara 🙏
Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) namaskaara greetings These are notes created while learning Kannada, hope it helps. Navigate to common phrases, if you are looking for quick use.
Simple Pronouns Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) naanu I/me naavu We niivu You (with respect) ivaru He/She - This person (with respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaru He/She - That person (with respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) niinu You (younger folk - without respect - singular) ivaLu She - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaLu She - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) ivanu He - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avanu He - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) &amp;ldquo;naanu&amp;rdquo; examples Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) naanu vidyaarthi I am a student naanu engineer I am an Engineer naanu Vaidya/Vaidye I am a Doctor (he/she) naanu grihiNi I am a home maker naanu nirudyOgi I am an un-employee naanu oLLeya huDugi I am a good girl naanu oLLeya huDuga I am a good boy naanu samshOdhaka/ki I am researcher (he/she) naanu oLLeya manushya I am good man / human being naanu oLLeya kelasagaara/kelasagaarti I am good worker Note:</description></item><item><title>shower-thoughts 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/shower-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/shower-thoughts/</guid><description>[2023-03-31] Movies in general use good looking people to sell their story. It is a visual medium afterall. ​* [2022-10-22] * &amp;ldquo;Save for Later&amp;rdquo; - Are we becoming collective procastinators? Save this article for later -&amp;gt; Pockets, One-tab, Reddit-save, Twitter-Bookmark, all these apps/features are building procastination in us. How many of us go back to that saved thread or article?
~timeline(NA) Indian traffic behaves how sediments behave in the water, gravitationally pulled towards the signal.</description></item><item><title>words ✍️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/words/</guid><description>​
Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company ​
Anger memory of pain in the past messenger that shows you that something important to you is being betrayed, squashed, or overlooked. A boundary, a value, a desire. Don&amp;rsquo;t kill (supress) that messenger (ofcourse don&amp;rsquo;t react). best remedy is to delay (any reaction) understand the source, when you get irritated, write and explain the feelings, it might help in identifying the source &amp;ldquo;The opposite of anger is not calmness, its empathy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Mehmet Oz ​</description></item></channel></rss>