<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes 📄 on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes 📄 on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding and Embracing Introversion</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</guid><description>Introversion has been a popular term in the pop culture since the past few years. While there is a wealth of information and resources available on introversion, understanding and dealing with this trait can still feel overwhelming or confusing.
In this article, I aim to simplify and distill some of the key principles of introversion, and share few tips for living and working with this personality trait, I have learnt and come across.</description></item><item><title>Rules of Engagement in a Community</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/rules-of-engagement/</guid><description>​
Community culture has become increasingly popular in recent years due to the growing recognition of the importance of social connection and the power of collective action to effect change.
​
What is community? A community can be defined as a group of people who share a common interest, goal, or identity and come together to support each other, share ideas, and collaborate on projects or initiatives.
​
General engagement rules one should follow Every community has its own set of unspoken rules of engagement, which may vary depending on the nature of the community, its values, and the people who participate in it.</description></item><item><title>'Acko on AIR - Subrata Mitra, Abhinav Chaturvedi (Accel Partners)' with Varun</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</guid><description>​
Talk: Acko on AIR - Subrata, Abhinav (Accel Partners, Acko&amp;rsquo;s first investors) - at Acko townhall
Notes:
Anecdote by Abhinav - Sachin Bansal (his then colleague at Amazon) fixed code in amazon payment for which the team was struggling (system was crashing completely when running a test suite cos of which they were unable to launch) Flipkart initial investment by Subrata - 3.5 cr for 25% - everytime they would come they talk about something they fixed (everyday) - committed to the cause When looking for investment - references from networks matter (Accel will ask Varun for Acko&amp;rsquo;s employee) Why most startups fail get to some scale as quickly as possible (zero to one) not having sharp focus (anti of why win - having a sharp focus) team dynamics don&amp;rsquo;t workout, going out in different directions Advice to youngsters Abhinav, Subrata - work with really good people, it compounds (good mentor) Subrata - really enjoy working whatever you do Varun - stay with a team for long time (5yrs or so it takes to crack a market) - everything compounds - your skills, your market value, your networks (you don&amp;rsquo;t restart everytime) One trait which Abhinav looks for in early founders - mentally and physically fit - it is tough to maintain Acko vision - 10Bn dollar (by 2030), in market that compounds Make companies in bust (startup bubble, less distractions), they will come out on top (strong) when the market is out of bust, market cycle again starts (happened multiple times in past - 9/11, 2008 etc)</description></item><item><title>'Masters of Scale - Eric Schmidt with Reid Hoffman</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</guid><description>​
Eric Schmidt was Executive Chairman of Google’s parent company, Alphabet, Inc. From 2001 to 2011 he was CEO of Google. Previously, he was CEO of Novell and before that a long-time executive at Sun Microsystems.
Notes:
HOFFMAN: Amit eventually built a tool that accurately predicts how much revenue the company had at any given time, down to the second. Pranks and productivity tend to blend together at Google, which is why Eric doesn’t dwell on the question of why Amit moved in to begin with.</description></item><item><title>'Experimenting with content' by Sattvik Mishra</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</guid><description> ​
Talk: Sattvik Mishra: Experimenting with content
Who: ScoopWhoop CEO
SOTS:
Traditional media houses prioritizes news for you (in a generic way, by giving more space on newspaper and time on tv-shows, also by ordering and grouping same genre together) News is subjective, for some it could be a spoiler in game of thrones, for others it could be sports. To create awareness on unconventional topics, make it relatable. For example: budget to 18yo</description></item><item><title>Are you joking me?</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</guid><description>​
With the advent of Internet, the meme culture and standup comedy culture has blasted in the last few years.
Internet has not only enabled the reach via social networks,
People could try out different material not only cheaply but also with the ease of a click. The showoff of facebook check-ins and instagram stories have acted as catalyst in the expansion of the gig culture. Gags I found funny (likeness is subjective):</description></item><item><title>Learn Kannada Learn 🧑‍🎓️</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/learning-kannada/</guid><description>Namaskaara 🙏
Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) namaskaara greetings These are notes created while learning Kannada, hope it helps. Navigate to common phrases, if you are looking for quick use.
Pronouns Nominative Pronouns Kannada (transliterated) English (translated) naanu I/me naavu We niivu You (with respect) ivaru He/She - This person (with respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaru He/She - That person (with respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) niinu You (without respect - singular) ivaLu She - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avaLu She - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) ivanu He - This person (without respect) (proximate - &amp;ldquo;यह&amp;rdquo;) avanu He - That person (without respect) (remote - &amp;ldquo;वो&amp;rdquo;) Notes:</description></item><item><title>opinions</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/opinions/</guid><description>Generally anything mainstream is cringe
Alcohol is considered bad because it causes one to lose control over senses. Anything that causes one to lose control over their senses is bad.
Golden rule of partying. One party Two Drinks Main purpose is Socialising. It’s a platform to meet people and make new friends not to get drunk. The loss of bodily control that comes with alcohol or drugs is fun. Do it, but within the confines of a controlled, safe environment where you are not likely to do anything you&amp;rsquo;ll regret when you have regained control.</description></item><item><title>shower-thoughts 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/my/shower-thoughts/</guid><description>2024-01-28
People mirror you, if you put out strong opinions, they do too. Does this happen when people like you? they mirror you? In a way, yes, they want to prove themselves in the eyes of the opposite person. They do that. Dating on apps is like doing crowdwork, asking what you do, why is a horse in your photo etc. ~2024
I come from the India where A Hindu has to prove his secularism and a Musim has to prove his nationalism constantly.</description></item><item><title>thought experiments 🤔</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/thought-experiments/</guid><description>Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t we live in Fantasy world? https://www.reddit.com/r/Buddhism/comments/x2mk3f/why_we_shouldnt_live_in_a_fantasy/
What is Spirit/Soul? What are the properties of it? If it&amp;rsquo;s not physical, lets say you get a brain injury, is your soul the same? your personality comes out differently after that. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it affect your soul?
What is consciousness?</description></item></channel></rss>