<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on wilspi | Sourabh</title><link>https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on wilspi | Sourabh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'The Ego and The Id' By Sigmund Freud - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/the-ego-and-the-id/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/the-ego-and-the-id/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The Ego and the Id&amp;rdquo; (1923) is a prominent paper (also book) by Sigmund Freud, the founder of psychoanalysis.
The book formulates the structural personality model in which he articulates a map of the different layers which comprise the human soul: the conscious, unconscious and preconscious which correlate with the faculties of ego, id and super-ego.
Captures Chapter 1: Consciousness and What is Unconscious
‘Being conscious’ is in the first place a purely descriptive term, resting on perception of the most immediate and certain character.</description></item><item><title>'The Liberation of Sita' By Volga - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/the-liberation-of-sita/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/the-liberation-of-sita/</guid><description>Thoughts Does Ramayana qualify for a feminist fiction?
For argument&amp;rsquo;s sake, lets consider Ramayana is a true story.
Post Ram and Sita&amp;rsquo;s homecoming, Sita was asked to give a chastity test, and she left the palace after proving herself. She could have left without undergoing the test but then the crowd would have believed that indeed she was at fault.
Being a woman and fighting for yourself in those ages is feministic (and applause worthy).</description></item><item><title>'Parasyte' By Hitoshi Iwaaki - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/parasyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/parasyte/</guid><description>Parasyte is a manga/anime that deals on some pretty heavy subjects regarding the existence of humans.
Thoughts Are humans parasytes? Favourite Moments This scene in chapter-48, it was a powerful scene. The arc seems to complete here</description></item><item><title>'Ghachar Ghochar' By Vivek Shanbhag - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/ghachar-ghochar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/ghachar-ghochar/</guid><description>A look into the lives of an Indian household with all its perjudices and beautiful memories.
Captures someone who simply sits there for so long must have a thousand wheels spinning in his head.
‘Sir – one story, many sides.’
Words after all are nothing by themselves. They burst into meaning only in the minds they’ve entered. At times, I’m tempted to unburden myself to him. But then, what’s the point when he seems to know without being told?</description></item><item><title>'Animal Farm' By George Orwell - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/animal-farm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/animal-farm/</guid><description>The book is a satire on Communism.
Fun Facts It was written between 1943 and 1945, and since Britain, US and Soviet Union had good relations, majority publication houses refused to publish the book. Summary Chapter 1:
After Mr. Jones, the owner of Manor Farm, falls asleep in a drunken stupor, all of his animals meet in the big barn at the request of old Major, a 12-year-old pig. Major delivers a rousing political speech about the evils inflicted upon them by their human keepers and their need to rebel against the tyranny of Man.</description></item><item><title>'The Count Of Monte Cristo' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/the-count-of-monte-cristo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/the-count-of-monte-cristo/</guid><description>In 2019, a colleague, with similar appetite as mine, recommended me to read &amp;lsquo;The Count of Monte Cristo&amp;rsquo; describing it as the best revenge story there is, and after deliberating on it for some time, I finally took the plunge.
The book is not yet complete, but will keep adding my thoughts and notes here.
​
Thoughts on the book Hard vocabulary - The book is from centuries back and people spoke and wrote in a different form.</description></item><item><title>'The Cathedral and The Bazaar' By Eric S. Raymond - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</guid><description>The Cathedral and the Bazaar (abbreviated CatB)
Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary is an essay, and later a book, by Eric S. Raymond
Focal points: Every good work of software starts by scratching a developer's personal itch. Too often software developers spend their days grinding away for pay at programs they neither need nor love To solve an interesting problem, start by finding a problem that is interesting to you.</description></item><item><title>'The Art of War' By Sun Tzu - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/the-art-of-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/the-art-of-war/</guid><description>Summary Calculation When you encounter a conflict in your life, before you act, seek out a solitary place that balances and enhances your mind to spiritually think things through.
Face the conflict and pro-actively seek to understand what lies at its root. An enemy or adversary is someone who seeks to do you harm. You and your family no doubt have disagreements, but everyone works for the same goals. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to subdue those you love and care about; you want to support them.</description></item><item><title>Beautiful Quotes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/quotes/</guid><description>​
Impatience with actions, patience with results.
&amp;ndash; Naval
​
Your heart needs to break multiple times for it to open up.
&amp;ndash; Rumi
​
Education is not the learning of facts, but the training of the mind to think
&amp;ndash; Albert Einstein
​
And those who were seen dancing were thought to be insane by those who could not hear the music.
&amp;ndash; Friedrich Nietzsche
​
Somewhere in the process of maturing into adults, most humans misunderstood comfort for happiness.</description></item><item><title>standup comedy</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</guid><description>​
With the advent of Internet, the meme culture and standup comedy culture has blasted in the last few years.
Internet has not only enabled the reach via social networks,
People could try out different material not only cheaply but also with the ease of a click. The showoff of facebook check-ins and instagram stories have acted as catalyst in the expansion of the gig culture. Good gags (likeness is subjective):</description></item><item><title>Words</title><link>https://wilspi.com/words/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/words/</guid><description>​
Alone Living alone teaches you the importance of someone&amp;rsquo;s company ​
Anger memory of pain in the past messenger that shows you that something important to you is being betrayed, squashed, or overlooked. A boundary, a value, a desire. Don&amp;rsquo;t kill (supress) that messenger (ofcourse don&amp;rsquo;t react). best remedy is to delay (any reaction) understand the source, when you get irritated, write and explain the feelings, it might help in identifying the source ​</description></item></channel></rss>