<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>notes on wilspi</title><link>https://wilspi.com/notes/</link><description>Recent content in notes on wilspi</description><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to deal with introversion</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/introversion/</guid><description>introversion falls into 2 categories
not by choice - shyness, low self esteem etc. if this is the cause, it needs to be worked on. by choice - for example schizoid personality or typical case where one doesnt find most people &amp;lsquo;interesting enough&amp;rsquo;. these people can talk with interesting people for hours but on average are not talkative. this is okay, we dont need to disorderize this. Introvert - Extrovert is a spectrum.</description></item><item><title>'A Marriage Knot' By Shobana Mahadevan - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-a-marriage-knot/</guid><description>Thoughts Feel good book Classic love story, uses common tropes aunt is bad, uncle is good but helpless, mother-in-law is good and supportive the female lead gets saved by a prince (in terms of both qualities and riches) and she is looking for basic respect and freedom - classic damsel in distress the male lead gets pushed by the female lead and he acknowledges his responsibilities and finds his strength, he gets challenged by the female&amp;rsquo;s thought process and in turn keeps falling for her both complete each other, opposites attract (if both complement each other), which is the case here No strong conflict: Both (female and male leads) lack any negative trait, the resolution of their conflict is merely a conversation away - what they agreed upon and what they want now Captures Look dear.</description></item><item><title>'Games People Play' By Eric Berne - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-games-people-play/</guid><description>​
First published in the 1960s and recognized as a classic work of its kind by professionals, the bestselling &amp;lsquo;Games People Play&amp;rsquo; is also an accessible and fascinating read. It is a wise, original, witty and very sensible analysis of the games we play in order to live with one another and with ourselves.
Captures Chapter 1
the most favoured forms of stimuli are those provided by physical intimacy
In technical language, an ego state may be described phenomenologically as a coherent system of feelings, and operationally as a set of coherent behaviour patterns.</description></item><item><title>'Acko on AIR - Subrata Mitra, Abhinav Chaturvedi (Accel Partners)' with Varun</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-acko-on-air-accel/</guid><description>​
Talk: Acko on AIR - Subrata, Abhinav (Accel Partners, Acko&amp;rsquo;s first investors) - at Acko townhall
Notes:
Anecdote by Abhinav - Sachin Bansal (his then colleague at Amazon) fixed code in amazon payment for which the team was struggling (system was crashing completely when running a test suite cos of which they were unable to launch) Flipkart initial investment by Subrata - 3.5 cr for 25% - everytime they would come they talk about something they fixed (everyday) - committed to the cause When looking for investment - references from networks matter (Accel will ask Varun for Acko&amp;rsquo;s employee) Why most startups fail get to some scale as quickly as possible (zero to one) not having sharp focus (anti of why win - having a sharp focus) team dynamics don&amp;rsquo;t workout, going out in different directions Advice to youngsters Abhinav, Subrata - work with really good people, it compounds (good mentor) Subrata - really enjoy working whatever you do Varun - stay with a team for long time (5yrs or so it takes to crack a market) - everything compounds - your skills, your market value, your networks (you don&amp;rsquo;t restart everytime) One trait which Abhinav looks for in early founders - mentally and physically fit - it is tough to maintain Acko vision - 10Bn dollar (by 2030), in market that compounds Make companies in bust (startup bubble, less distractions), they will come out on top (strong) when the market is out of bust, market cycle again starts (happened multiple times in past - 9/11, 2008 etc)</description></item><item><title>'Masters of Scale - Eric Schmidt' with Reid Hoffman</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/masters-of-scale-eric-schmidt/</guid><description>​
Eric Schmidt was Executive Chairman of Google’s parent company, Alphabet, Inc. From 2001 to 2011 he was CEO of Google. Previously, he was CEO of Novell and before that a long-time executive at Sun Microsystems.
Notes:
HOFFMAN: Amit eventually built a tool that accurately predicts how much revenue the company had at any given time, down to the second. Pranks and productivity tend to blend together at Google, which is why Eric doesn’t dwell on the question of why Amit moved in to begin with.</description></item><item><title>'The Ego and The Id' By Sigmund Freud - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-ego-and-the-id/</guid><description>​
&amp;ldquo;The Ego and the Id&amp;rdquo; (1923) is a prominent paper (also book) by Sigmund Freud, the founder of psychoanalysis.
The book formulates the structural personality model in which he articulates a map of the different layers which comprise the human soul: the conscious, unconscious and preconscious which correlate with the faculties of ego, id and super-ego.
​
Captures Chapter 1: Consciousness and What is Unconscious
‘Being conscious’ is in the first place a purely descriptive term, resting on perception of the most immediate and certain character.</description></item><item><title>'The Liberation of Sita' By Volga - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-liberation-of-sita/</guid><description>​
Thoughts Does Ramayana qualify for a feminist fiction?
Post Ram and Sita&amp;rsquo;s homecoming, Sita was asked to give a chastity test, and she left the palace after proving herself. She could have left without undergoing the test but then the public would have indeed believed that she was at fault.
Whether Ramayana is based on true events or if it&amp;rsquo;s a fictional tale it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, in either case Sita&amp;rsquo;s character is liberating.</description></item><item><title>Seven Deadly Sins</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/7-deadly-sins/</guid><description>​
The way we behave is mostly influenced by our surroundings (by law of averages you shall become average of folks you spend time with, over a long period of time) until and unless we mindfully start tweaking these behaviours.
Here, as the title suggests, I write about these conventional vices with the aim to define/understand them better, most of which are the basis of our sufferings.
The seven deadly sins, also known as the capital vices or cardinal sins, is a grouping and classification of vices within Christian teachings.</description></item><item><title>'Parasyte' By Hitoshi Iwaaki - Manga Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/manga-parasyte/</guid><description>Parasyte is a manga/anime that deals on some pretty heavy subjects regarding the existence of humans.
Thoughts Are humans parasytes? Action Favourite Moments This scene in chapter-48, it was a powerful scene. The arc seems to complete here</description></item><item><title>Intention Vs Action - framework to prioritise yourself</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-action/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/intention-vs-action/</guid><description>​
Whenever we are hurt/harmed or have been at the end of an unsatisfying or unfavourable situation, we replay the situation and try to judge each and every action, of ourselves and of others. We often reflect upon the incident from various lenses.
There are frameworks to better understand and analyse your/others&amp;rsquo; actions, one such framework that has helped me to judge these situations is &amp;ldquo;Intention Vs Action&amp;rdquo;.
​
Why Intention Vs Action?</description></item><item><title>'Ghachar Ghochar' By Vivek Shanbhag - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-ghachar-ghochar/</guid><description>A look into the lives of an Indian household with all its perjudices and beautiful memories.
Captures someone who simply sits there for so long must have a thousand wheels spinning in his head.
‘Sir – one story, many sides.’
Words after all are nothing by themselves. They burst into meaning only in the minds they’ve entered. At times, I’m tempted to unburden myself to him. But then, what’s the point when he seems to know without being told?</description></item><item><title>'Animal Farm' By George Orwell - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-animal-farm/</guid><description>The book is a satire on Communism.
Fun Facts It was written between 1943 and 1945, and since Britain, US and Soviet Union had good relations, majority publication houses refused to publish the book. Summary Chapter 1:
After Mr. Jones, the owner of Manor Farm, falls asleep in a drunken stupor, all of his animals meet in the big barn at the request of old Major, a 12-year-old pig. Major delivers a rousing political speech about the evils inflicted upon them by their human keepers and their need to rebel against the tyranny of Man.</description></item><item><title>'The Count Of Monte Cristo' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-count-of-monte-cristo/</guid><description>​
In 2019, a colleague, with similar appetite as mine, recommended me to read &amp;lsquo;The Count of Monte Cristo&amp;rsquo; describing it as the best revenge story there is, and after deliberating on it for some time, I finally took the plunge.
The book is not yet complete, but will keep adding my thoughts and notes here.
​
Thoughts on the book Hard vocabulary - The book is from centuries back and people spoke and wrote in a different form.</description></item><item><title>'The Cathedral and The Bazaar' By Eric S. Raymond - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-cathedral-and-the-bazaar/</guid><description>​
The Cathedral and the Bazaar (abbreviated CatB)
Musings on Linux and Open Source by an Accidental Revolutionary is an essay, and later a book, by Eric S. Raymond
​
Focal points: Every good work of software starts by scratching a developer's personal itch. Too often software developers spend their days grinding away for pay at programs they neither need nor love To solve an interesting problem, start by finding a problem that is interesting to you.</description></item><item><title>'Experimenting with content' by Sattvik Mishra</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/talk-experimenting-with-content/</guid><description> ​
Talk: Sattvik Mishra: Experimenting with content
Who: ScoopWhoop CEO
SOTS:
Traditional media houses prioritizes news for you (in a generic way, by giving more space on newspaper and time on tv-shows, also by ordering and grouping same genre together) News is subjective, for some it could be a spoiler in game of thrones, for others it could be sports. To create awareness on unconventional topics, make it relatable. For example: budget to 18yo</description></item><item><title>'The Art of War' By Sun Tzu - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-the-art-of-war/</guid><description>​
Summary Calculation When you encounter a conflict in your life, before you act, seek out a solitary place that balances and enhances your mind to spiritually think things through.
Face the conflict and pro-actively seek to understand what lies at its root. An enemy or adversary is someone who seeks to do you harm. You and your family no doubt have disagreements, but everyone works for the same goals. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to subdue those you love and care about; you want to support them.</description></item><item><title>'Modern Romance' By Aziz Ansari - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-modern-romance/</guid><description>Captures “People will go as far as they have to to find a mate, but no farther.”
For the young people who got married in the 1950s, getting married was the first step in adulthood. After high school or college, you got married and you left the house. For today’s folks, marriage is usually one of the later stages in adulthood. Now most young people spend their twenties and thirties in another stage of life, where they go to university, start a career, and experience being an adult outside of their parents’ home before marriage.</description></item><item><title>'Bhagavad Gita' - Book Notes</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/book-bhagavad-gita/</guid><description>Translation by Winthrop Sargeant
Captures happiness and unhappiness are the same, is ready for immortality.
if you will not undertake this righteous war, thereupon, having avoided your own duty and glory, you shall incur evil.
Holding pleasure and pain to be alike, likewise gain and loss, victory and defeat then engage in battle! Thus you shall not incur evil.
be free from those three qualities, Arjuna, indifferent towards the pairs of opposites, eternally fixed in truth, free from thoughts of acquisition and comfort, and possessed of the Self.</description></item><item><title>Are you joking me?</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/standup-comedy/</guid><description>​
With the advent of Internet, the meme culture and standup comedy culture has blasted in the last few years.
Internet has not only enabled the reach via social networks,
People could try out different material not only cheaply but also with the ease of a click. The showoff of facebook check-ins and instagram stories have acted as catalyst in the expansion of the gig culture. Gags I found funny (likeness is subjective):</description></item><item><title>product sketches</title><link>https://wilspi.com/n/product-sketches/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://wilspi.com/n/product-sketches/</guid><description>​
Product Ideas Music Picker Picks or generates a Spotify playlist for you
I tell which artists I want to listen and it curates a playlist of best songs by each of them Pick-a-Book This is an idea for a utility application for avid book readers, favoring the mobile platform.
Often times in a library when we are searching for a book, we have to scan and go through each and every book&amp;rsquo;s title or author.</description></item></channel></rss>