<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brainstorm on Sourabh Deokar</title>
    <link>https://wilspi.com/categories/brainstorm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in brainstorm on Sourabh Deokar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 22:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wilspi.com/categories/brainstorm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Sketches</title>
      <link>https://wilspi.com/post/brainstorm/product-sketches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wilspi.com/post/brainstorm/product-sketches/</guid>
      <description>Cook me Feedback To have a better food experience with your cook, you have to constantly tell him about your likes and dislikes. Sometimes he/she might cook you a fantastic dinner (tried something new) and never know if you liked.
Whatsapp is good for chatting but not remembering, also your food habits are not structured and easily accessible within whatsapp and other note taking platforms. Also, privacy.
This app will give food recommendations and feedback to cook with regards to small repetitive things so that they know what works, and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch: Pick-a-Book</title>
      <link>https://wilspi.com/post/brainstorm/pick-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wilspi.com/post/brainstorm/pick-a-book/</guid>
      <description>This is an idea for an utility application for avid book readers, favoring mobile platform.
Often times in a library when we are searching for a book, we have to scan and go through each and every book&amp;rsquo;s title or author. This exercise is tough and draining. The pain goes multi fold when you are looking for multiple books or authors. Now imagine you have an app which scans and reads every book names, while you hold the mobile camera and stroll in the library, and the app flickers the screen to alert you that it found one of the books you were looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>